

Resume of Chris Rault

A front-end designer, ideas guy and digital nomad from South Africa >> Hoekwil, ZA (UTC+2) · chris@smokeyfro.com · linkedin.com/in/chrisrault

Statement

I am a seasoned front-end designer with 18+ years experience designing and implementing experiences for the web. I've helped worked with of all sizes, bootstrapped a number of digital products, helped create both the Morph and Beans frameworks and launched a number of fun projects on the side. I am currently excited about building sites and web apps using the JAM Stack.

Experience

Freelancer @ SmokeyFro Jun 2019 - Present

- Working on Mzango.com and other side projects.
- Consolodated a bunch of side projects under the SmokeyFro brand.
- JAM Stack site built using Vue.js/Gridsome and multiple data sources.

Developer @ WineFolly Dec 2017 - Jun 2019

- Redesigned and rebuilt the site using Beans, CMB2 and AMP Native.
- Implemented an interactive index of 260+ grapes and wines landing pages.
- Implemented a shortcode builder + suite of Gutenberg blocks.
- Created a compehensive style guide for the sites components.
- Solely responsible for the sites ongoing development / improvements.
- Ongoing performance optimisation and AB/Testing using Google Optimize.
- Built out a number of custom post types to manage the team, glossary, etc.
- Created landing pages for different marketing initiatives.
- Setup a number of import scripts to simplify data population.

Read the case-study: https://smokeyfro.com/work/winefolly

Creative Director @ Web Monkeys Jan 2005 - Dec 2017

- Oversaw the creative direction of our various product related brands.
- Implemented 30+ Joomla templates, built up a customer base of 30k.
- Co-founded the Morph template framework and admin interface.
- Managed a small team of developers and support staff all working remotely.
- Launched HeadwayRocket, with a number of plugins extending the Headway Visual Editor which turned over \$250k revenue in 5 years.
- Launched ThemeButler, a theme and plugin club aimed at WordPress developers, centered around our in-house open-source framework Beans.

Technical Consultant @ RPC Data Jan 2001 - Jun 2003

- Product lead for Oracles Forms and Reports, 9i Application Server and Portal
- Assisted sales team with technical demos, presentations and product info.
- Helped create in-house POS using Oracles suite of products.
- Was responsible for maintaining the companies site and internal portal.

Want to know more? View my full resume on https://smokevfro.com/work/resume

Education

Advanced Web Design University of Cape Town Jan 2001 - June 2002

National Senior Certificate Die Built Highschool, George Jan 1995 - Dec 1999

Skills

- + Web / UI / Theme Design
- + Web Development
- + Technical Writing
- + Customer Support
- + Screencasting / Tutorials
- + Wireframing / Prototyping
- + Performance Optimisation

Tools

- + PHP, HTML, CSS
- + Vue.js / jQuery / Vanilla JS
- + Gridsome / Svelte
- + Matamo Analytics / GA
- + Sanity / Cockpit / Ghost / WP
- + Zeit Now + CLI / Netlify
- + Git / Github / Gitlab
- + Lighthouse / Pingdom

References



Madeline Puckette CEO | Folly Inc Former employer



Thierry Muller
Engineer | Google
Former partner



John Coonen CEO, Coffee Group CMS Expo Organizer



Brandon McDonald CEO | RPC Data Former employer



